<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information Warfare on Denys Kolesnyk</title>
    <link>/tags/information-warfare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information Warfare on Denys Kolesnyk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/information-warfare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mental Warfare - Russian-style Cognitive Warfare</title>
      <link>/post/mental-warfare-russian-style-cognitive-warfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/mental-warfare-russian-style-cognitive-warfare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on January 27, 2023, on &lt;a href=&#34;https://infoops.fr/posts/la-guerre-mentale-la-guerre-cognitive-a-la-russe/&#34;&gt;Info Ops France&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In March 2021, Andrei Ilnitski, advisor to the Russian Defense Minister, declared that &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;the West, led by the United States, has unleashed a &lt;strong&gt;Mental Warfare&lt;/strong&gt; against Russia, the consequences of which will manifest themselves at least a generation later&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In August of the same year, he published an article entitled &amp;ldquo;Russia&amp;rsquo;s Mental Warfare&amp;rdquo; in the military-theoretical magazine Voyennaya Mysl&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (&lt;em&gt;from Russian - military thought&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France unveils a Cyber Influence Warfare doctrine</title>
      <link>/post/france-unveils-a-cyber-influence-warfare-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/france-unveils-a-cyber-influence-warfare-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/parly_burkhard.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a press conference on October 21, French Defense Minister Florence Parly and Army Chief of Staff General Thierry Burkhard presented the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defense.gouv.fr/sites/default/files/ema/Doctrine%20de%20lutte%20informatique%20d%25u2019influence%20%28L2I%29.pdf&#34;&gt;Military Doctrine of Cyber Influence Warfare&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Doctrine militaire de lutte informatique d&amp;rsquo;influence - L2I&lt;/em&gt;). The publication of &amp;ldquo;public elements&amp;rdquo; of this doctrine may indicate that France recognizes and assumes the conduct of information operations, including on social media, but also demonstrates that a gap at a doctrinal level that exists in relation to Russia or China is shrinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia adopts a new National Security Strategy</title>
      <link>/post/russia-adopts-a-new-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/russia-adopts-a-new-national-security-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After around a year and a half of work on Russia&amp;rsquo;s new &lt;a href=&#34;http://static.kremlin.ru/media/events/files/ru/QZw6hSk5z9gWq0plD1ZzmR5cER0g5tZC.pdf&#34;&gt;National Security Strategy (NSS)&lt;/a&gt;, the process was finally completed on June 2 with the publication of Decree No. 400. This document, signed by Russian President Vladimir Putin, replaces the old NSS in force since December 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The publication of the strategic document was delayed, most likely due to the presidential elections in the United States, which consequently gave rise to the need to assess the positions of the new master of the White House and to adjust certain paragraphs of the document and adapt the language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Reflexive Control</title>
      <link>/post/on-reflexive-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/on-reflexive-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In democracies, public opinion lies at the very heart of how society functions and is a factor that influences decision-making by the authorities. However, public opinion can not only exert pressure on the government in decision-making, but the government can also take steps to influence public opinion to support its decision or create support for reform. But with the advent of digital technology and the massive proliferation of the Internet, public opinion can be shaped from the outside, particularly by foreign powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Warfare according to Col. Komov</title>
      <link>/post/information-warfare-according-to-komov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/information-warfare-according-to-komov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is high time to delve into the work of Colonel and Professor Sergei Komov, a Soviet and later Russian theorist who stands as one of the most influential figures in the realm of Information Warfare. The reason for focusing on Komov is clear: despite his significant contributions, he remains relatively unknown, particularly among French-speaking experts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Komov has authored several articles on Information Warfare, or what he terms the &amp;ldquo;Information Struggle.&amp;rdquo; Today, we explore two of his pieces published in the Russian journal Voyennaia mysl (Military Thought) during the 1990s. While the earliest article I could locate was published in 1994, it is his 1996 article titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://militaryarticle.vibrokatok.by/voennaya-mysl/1996-vm/8775-informacionnaja-borba-v-sovremennoj-vojne-voprosy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Information Struggle in Modern Warfare: Theoretical Problems&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that truly captured my attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
