<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Denys Kolesnyk</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Denys Kolesnyk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grey Zone eliminated in Mali together with Russian mercenaries and the FAMa</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/grey-zone-eliminated-in-mali/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/grey-zone-eliminated-in-mali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in French on August 6, 2024, on &lt;a href=&#34;https://infoops.fr/posts/grey-zone-elimine-au-mali/&#34;&gt;Info Ops France&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of July 2024, a military convoy of the Malian Armed Forces (FAMa) supported by Russian mercenaries from Africa Corps (formerly Wagner) was eliminated near the town of Tinzaouatine in northern Mali by fighters from the Strategic Framework for the Defence of the People of Azawad (CSP-DPA). In this fight, the person behind the Telegram channel affiliated to the Russian mercenary galaxy &amp;ldquo;GREY ZONE&amp;rdquo;, nickname &amp;ldquo;Белый&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;from Russian - White&lt;/em&gt;) lost his life &amp;ldquo;with weapons in his hands&amp;rdquo;, according to the Russians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Warfare - Russian-style Cognitive Warfare</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/mental-warfare-russian-style-cognitive-warfare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/mental-warfare-russian-style-cognitive-warfare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on January 27, 2023, on &lt;a href=&#34;https://infoops.fr/posts/la-guerre-mentale-la-guerre-cognitive-a-la-russe/&#34;&gt;Info Ops France&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In March 2021, Andrei Ilnitski, advisor to the Russian Defense Minister, declared that &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;the West, led by the United States, has unleashed a &lt;strong&gt;Mental Warfare&lt;/strong&gt; against Russia, the consequences of which will manifest themselves at least a generation later&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In August of the same year, he published an article entitled &amp;ldquo;Russia&amp;rsquo;s Mental Warfare&amp;rdquo; in the military-theoretical magazine Voyennaya Mysl&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (&lt;em&gt;from Russian - military thought&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discursus de bello Moscovitico</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/discursus-de-bello-moscovitico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/discursus-de-bello-moscovitico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/niemirycz-discursus-de-bello-moscovitico.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Discursus de bello Moscovitico&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On February 24, 2022, Russia launched a full-scale invasion of Ukraine. It was considered an unlikely event given several factors, including the insufficient Russian troops amassed at the Ukrainian border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To date, the Russians have suffered many defeats, notably failing to capture Kyiv, make Ukraine surrender, or even take Kharkiv - a city barely 40 kilometres from the Russian border. The Russian army performed significantly less well than estimated, and almost three months after the start of the Russian invasion, it is unlikely that they&amp;rsquo;ll manage to achieve their goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does the Russian warmongering rhetoric hint at the invasion of Ukraine?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/does-the-russian-warmongering-rhetoric-hint-at-the-invasion-of-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/does-the-russian-warmongering-rhetoric-hint-at-the-invasion-of-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/russian_invasion_ukraine_bild.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original article was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://denkolesnyk.substack.com/p/does-the-russian-warmongering-rhetoric&#34;&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt; on December 6, 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the information about Russia massing troops near the Ukrainian border and fears of a possible invasion appeared in diverse Western media. The warmongering rhetoric also peaked in the Russian information space. The RAND’s Samuel Charap rushed to publish an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2021/11/19/ukraine-russia-putin-border-522989&#34;&gt;op-ed&lt;/a&gt; suggesting the change of approach to Russia that Biden&amp;rsquo;s administration has to undertake. He also advocated for Washington shifting the focus from “&lt;em&gt;only on coercing Russia&lt;/em&gt;” to “&lt;em&gt;also push Kyiv to take steps toward implementing its obligations under the Minsk II agreement&lt;/em&gt;”. The Minsk II that he, himself, described as “&lt;em&gt;victor’s peace, essentially imposed by Russia on Ukraine at the barrel of a gun&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France unveils a Cyber Influence Warfare doctrine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/france-unveils-a-cyber-influence-warfare-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/france-unveils-a-cyber-influence-warfare-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/parly_burkhard.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a press conference on October 21, French Defense Minister Florence Parly and Army Chief of Staff General Thierry Burkhard presented the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defense.gouv.fr/sites/default/files/ema/Doctrine%20de%20lutte%20informatique%20d%25u2019influence%20%28L2I%29.pdf&#34;&gt;Military Doctrine of Cyber Influence Warfare&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Doctrine militaire de lutte informatique d&amp;rsquo;influence - L2I&lt;/em&gt;). The publication of &amp;ldquo;public elements&amp;rdquo; of this doctrine may indicate that France recognizes and assumes the conduct of information operations, including on social media, but also demonstrates that a gap at a doctrinal level that exists in relation to Russia or China is shrinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Information Confrontation a new Russian concept?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/is-information-confrontation-a-new-russian-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/is-information-confrontation-a-new-russian-concept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the publication of Russia&amp;rsquo;s new &lt;a href=&#34;https://kolesnyk.fr/post/russia-adopts-a-new-national-security-strategy/&#34;&gt;National Security Strategy&lt;/a&gt; (NSS) last June, some Western experts began talking about &amp;ldquo;informational confrontation&amp;rdquo;. In particular, Michel Duclos of the Institut Montaigne published an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.institutmontaigne.org/blog/la-strategie-de-securite-nationale-russe-2021-lheure-de-la-confrontation-informationnelle&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; entitled &amp;ldquo;Russia&amp;rsquo;s National Security Strategy 2021: time for informational confrontation&amp;rdquo;, while Sergey Sukhankin of the Jamestown Foundation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.la-croix.com/Monde/France-menacee-linfluence-russe-pre-carre-africain-2021-10-19-1201181313&#34;&gt;discussed&lt;/a&gt; information confrontation in the context of the use of the Russian private military company Wagner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case, the word seems to have caught on. So the question arises: Is this a new concept or a new Russian approach?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia adopts a new National Security Strategy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/russia-adopts-a-new-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/russia-adopts-a-new-national-security-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After around a year and a half of work on Russia&amp;rsquo;s new &lt;a href=&#34;http://static.kremlin.ru/media/events/files/ru/QZw6hSk5z9gWq0plD1ZzmR5cER0g5tZC.pdf&#34;&gt;National Security Strategy (NSS)&lt;/a&gt;, the process was finally completed on June 2 with the publication of Decree No. 400. This document, signed by Russian President Vladimir Putin, replaces the old NSS in force since December 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The publication of the strategic document was delayed, most likely due to the presidential elections in the United States, which consequently gave rise to the need to assess the positions of the new master of the White House and to adjust certain paragraphs of the document and adapt the language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia and Iran sign information security cooperation agreement</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/russia-and-iran-sign-information-security-cooperation-agreement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/russia-and-iran-sign-information-security-cooperation-agreement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 26th of January, Russia and Iran signed a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mddoc.mid.ru/api/ia/download/?uuid=451cab2c-c651-471b-9e96-35a5793e8053&#34;&gt;cooperation agreement in the field of information security&lt;/a&gt;. The agreement was signed in Moscow during a visit by Iran&amp;rsquo;s Foreign Minister, Mohammad Javad Zarif.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that Russia has signed similar agreements in the past, notably within the framework of the Collective Security Treaty Organisation (CSTO) and the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS). Moscow has also concluded similar agreements at a bilateral level, albeit with some differences. These include cooperation agreements in the field of international information security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Reflexive Control</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/on-reflexive-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/on-reflexive-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In democracies, public opinion lies at the very heart of how society functions and is a factor that influences decision-making by the authorities. However, public opinion can not only exert pressure on the government in decision-making, but the government can also take steps to influence public opinion to support its decision or create support for reform. But with the advent of digital technology and the massive proliferation of the Internet, public opinion can be shaped from the outside, particularly by foreign powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vladislav Surkov on &#34;Putin&#39;s long state&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/vladislav-surkov-on-putin-long-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/vladislav-surkov-on-putin-long-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/vladislav-sourkov.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, Vladislav Surkov, the man behind the &amp;ldquo;power vertical&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sovereign democracy&amp;rdquo; concept of Vladimir Putin&amp;rsquo;s first presidential term, published an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ng.ru/ideas/2019-02-11/5_7503_surkov.html&#34;&gt;opinion piece&lt;/a&gt; entitled &amp;ldquo;Putin&amp;rsquo;s long state&amp;rdquo;. In his article, he sets out his views on several topics, including elections, the Russian state, international relations, and other issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He explains that &amp;ldquo;Putin&amp;rsquo;s political machine&amp;rdquo; is only getting bigger, and predicts that within several years Russia will remain &amp;ldquo;Putin&amp;rsquo;s state&amp;rdquo;. He goes even further, referring to &amp;ldquo;Putinism&amp;rdquo; as an ideology of the future. According to him, the Russian political system is not only useful for his country&amp;rsquo;s future but &amp;ldquo;clearly has significant export potential&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Warfare according to Col. Komov</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/information-warfare-according-to-komov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/information-warfare-according-to-komov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is high time to delve into the work of Colonel and Professor Sergei Komov, a Soviet and later Russian theorist who stands as one of the most influential figures in the realm of Information Warfare. The reason for focusing on Komov is clear: despite his significant contributions, he remains relatively unknown, particularly among French-speaking experts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Komov has authored several articles on Information Warfare, or what he terms the &amp;ldquo;Information Struggle.&amp;rdquo; Today, we explore two of his pieces published in the Russian journal Voyennaia mysl (Military Thought) during the 1990s. While the earliest article I could locate was published in 1994, it is his 1996 article titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://militaryarticle.vibrokatok.by/voennaya-mysl/1996-vm/8775-informacionnaja-borba-v-sovremennoj-vojne-voprosy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Information Struggle in Modern Warfare: Theoretical Problems&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that truly captured my attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/dk_pic.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Denys Kolesnyk is a French analyst and consultant based in Paris. He specializes in security and defense issues in Central and Eastern Europe, including Poland, Ukraine and Russia. In particular, he focuses on Information Warfare and influence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He has worked at the NATO Liaison Office, with Effective Engagement Strategies, and as a consultant for numerous other entities. 2022 he founded &lt;a href=&#34;https://infoops.fr/&#34;&gt;Info Ops France&lt;/a&gt; - an initiative aimed at improving the informational resilience of French society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the media</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Comment for El Periódico (Catalonia, Spain): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elperiodico.com/es/internacional/20250224/inflacion-menos-libertades-precio-rusia-guerra-ucrania-114552231&#34;&gt;Inflación y menos libertades: el precio que paga Rusia por tres años de guerra en Ucrania&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comment for Le Parisien (France): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.leparisien.fr/international/etats-unis/je-pense-que-nous-perdrons-pourquoi-zelensky-affirme-que-la-survie-de-lukraine-depend-des-etats-unis-20-11-2024-X4AOMAKBLJDPNPY5O7JQFCGMOU.php&#34;&gt;« Je pense que nous perdrons » : pourquoi Zelensky affirme que la survie de l’Ukraine dépend des États-Unis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intervention at TVP World (Poland): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AIqKG7iomkI&#34;&gt;Le Pen Verdict Could Mean Political Ban, 18 November 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comment for Le Parisien (France): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.leparisien.fr/international/craintes-dune-attaque-de-moscou-dici-2030-comment-la-russie-seme-les-graines-dune-future-guerre-16-10-2024-NWBIIDWPAVEUXJFER3KV2F2YPA.php&#34;&gt;Craintes d’une attaque de Moscou d’ici 2030 : comment la Russie sème les graines d’une future guerre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
